

# Md.Maruf Islam Web Developer



- maruf4426@diu.edu.bd
- S islammaruf.github.io





#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Jan 2020 - Present

#### Software Programmer at Colgis BD Ltd.

Developed Employee, Product, Product Description, Customer - portion of the master module of the warehouse management system.

Developed Order Entry, Order history - portion of the order module for the

Developed Deposit input, Delivery input - portion of the sales module

Collaborate with QC and Frontend Developers to develop the system.

#### Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

#### Software Engineer at Skylark Soft Limited

Developed vehicle management module, order & purchase order module, purchase requisition & purchase receive - the portion of inventory system module and generate a report like order confirmation list, order recap summary report depends on dates for ERP System.

Developed a Chat system between the different users using pusher for ERP System.

Developed leads, contacts, opportunities, accounts in CRM System. URL: http://139.162.49.51:33/.

Developed payment gateway with FastSpring API and sign in, sign up with google account for Offcutter.com a SaaS based service. URL: http://offcutter.com/.



## **ABOUT ME**

I'm a Web Developer - having an understanding of Object-Oriented Programming and Database Design, have hands-on experience with PHP, JavaScript, Laravel, jQuery, REST API. Currently, I am working at Colgis BD LTD. I like to work with my team and love to share and gather knowledge.



### **EDUCATION**

Sep 2014 - Jan 2019 BSC in CSE **CGPA:** 3.2 out of 4.0

Daffodil International University



#### **SKILLS**

Understanding the fully synchronous behavior of PHP.

Knowledge of Object-oriented PHP programming.

Understanding of MVC design patterns.

Knowledge of core Laravel features like - request life cycle, service container, service provider, dependency injection.

Creating database schemas that represent and support business processes.

Integration of multiple data sources and databases into one system.

Familiarity with SQL/NoSQL databases and their declarative guery languages like MySQL and Mongo DB.

Knowledge on JavaScript core concepts like scope, IIFE, hoisting, closures, callbacks, prototype and prototypal inheritance and es6.

Strong understanding of features and utility functions of jQuery.

Ability to adapt various jQuery features, such as "\$. ajax", to specific needs.

Familiarity with input validation techniques and approaches with JavaScript.

Ability to roll out well-implemented custom jQuery plugins.

Basic understanding of web markup, including HTML5 and CSS3.

Strong understanding of code versioning tools, such as git.

Basic knowledge of React IS and its workflow like React router, React redux and Redux-thunk.

Familiarity with Node JS specific framework express JS and it's workflow.

Try to follow SOLID design pattern and keep code clean as much as possible.

Ability to understand business requirements and translate them into technical requirements.